She turned out that way
because I wasn't with her.
And I was going on about how
I didn't want her to look sad...
Emilia, are you okay?
I'll save Emilia...
and the Sanctuary, and the mansion, too.
I'll save every last one of them,
if it costs me my life.
Are you feeling all right?
Yes... because Subaru was
there for me, I think.
The biggest problem is Roswaal.
He knew that I've been looping,
even if he didn't know that
I have to die to do it.
He's obviously following the Tome of Wisdom.
He won't condone anything that
goes against what's written,
and if it does, he won't balk
at using my loops to redo it.
What's forcing him to do all that?
I...
By doing that...
you can become like me.
...won't ever be like you.
Not ever.
So... is it okay if I turn to you again?
There are so many things I want to find
out and get you to agonize over with me.
Invite me, Echidna!
I'll give you my life as many
times as you want it!
Or my pride or anything else!
So please, Echidna!
Let me...
Behold an unthinkable present.
Huh?
...iar.
Liar.
Liar! Liar! Liar!
Liar! Liar! Subaru, you liar!
What... is this?
Emilia-sama!
You liar!
Subaru... Subaru... You liar...
Felis! Come here at once!
This is urgent! Hurry!
You said... we'd be together...
I don't recognize this...
I don't recognize this scenario.
Old Man Wil!
How could I recognize it?
His throat's been stabbed!
We haven't a moment to lose!
Stop... It's no use. He's already dead.
I won't let you die!
I won't let the one who
saved me die in this way!
Why did this have to happen now?
Stop joking! Stop fooling around with us!
Stop it... Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
It's too late. His soul is already gone.
Why? Why?!
Why did you die so easily?
Subaru-dono, you are...
Weakling. Coward.
You're leaving behind everyone you cared about,
forcing all of the pain and suffering on us.
You said...
You said... that you loved me.
Was that...
...how that world looked after I died?
Or was it the trial? Not really my past,
but the second trial?
Behold an unthinkable present.
Subaru?
Emilia-sama, please...
Wipe Subaru's face for him.
Why?
Why does Subaru look like this?
Why did this have to happen to him?
To save me?
Why? Please tell me.
I wanted to speak with
you more, Natsuki Subaru.
I wanted to call you a friend.
Stop... it...
Please...
Stop it!
Behold an unthinkable present.
After all that nonsense you kept spouting...
Was this all part of your
plan as well, Beatrice-sama?
Why?
I knew you couldn't be "that person."
But still...
This is what you call "love"? Honestly...
There's no help for you.
Behold an unthinkable present.
So it is you.
Emilia-sama and Subaru are
both gone now, aren't they?
Lia is asleep. Forever.
I don't want to exist in a world without her.
Therefore, per our contract,
I will freeze this world solid.
He and I are equally guilty.
And that is why you're trying
to destroy the world?
I am going to stop you from
causing any further harm.
If you must resent someone, please resent me.
I don't resent anyone, Reinhard.
You are a true hero.
And a hero is all you can be.
Behold an unthinkable present.
And that's the end of it.
This wasn't a very rewarding job at all.
Behold an unthinkable present.
I only prevented the situation from worsening.
I could tell that Subaru-kun
was already beyond help.
Surely he wanted me to end
it as quickly as possible.
Behold an unthinkable present.
Can you no longer stand, Subaru-kun?
This can't be real.
It is real.
I will be by your side whenever
you wish it, Subaru-kun.
Rem...
Yes. I am your Rem.
Yes, I am Rem.
Your very own, all-purpose,
ever-useful maid.
You...
Are you all right? Are you tired?
I don't know...
Maybe I am tired.
But I haven't even done anything yet...
If I were stronger, smarter,
and capable of a lot more,
they wouldn't have had to
hurt and suffer so much.
Subaru-kun...
If the world was still going on after I died,
how many times did I just
leave them all to die?
Subaru-kun...
How many times did I let you die?
How many times do I have to kill you?!
Subaru-kun.
It's all right.
Rem...
I love you.
I love you, Subaru-kun.
So everything will be all right.
Th-That doesn't... answer anything...
It does.
Holding you the way I am right now
is the answer to everything.
You've been through so much, Subaru-kun.
You suffered so much pain all alone...
But you don't need to feel
so sad all the time anymore.
I...
I will take the place of
everything you're feeling.
Just entrust everything to me,
and just rest for now.
All you need to do is sleep.
Rem...
It's easy to give up.
But it doesn't suit you.
Who are you?
Huh?
I'm asking you who you are.
S-Subaru-kun, what are you—
I knew that when I was at the end of my rope,
clutching my knees and wallowing in anguish,
you would come and stay gently by my side.
You'd listen to my troubles,
let me vent my insecurities,
and wring everything out of
me until my tears ran dry...
And then you'd say, "Now, stand up."
You wouldn't tell me to just rest.
You wouldn't tell me to give up
and entrust everything to you.
You like me and I like you,
you're good to me and you love me,
but you're also stricter
with me than anyone else.
Rem is the one girl who doesn't go easy on me!
You're wrong! Please listen
to me, Subaru-kun!
I just don't want to see you suffering so—
I'll show you my weakness and my fragility.
But I'll never let you see me give up!
Because you are my hero, Subaru-kun!
Get out of here, you fraud!
Don't you dare coddle me
with Rem's face and voice!
Th-This isn't... what I...
was told... t-to expect...
Huh?
And who are you?
I-I'm Carmilla, th-the Witch of Lust.
N-Nice to meet... you...
Is this weird place part of Echidna's dream?
What were you trying to pull earlier?!
Earlier?
I'm talking about you coming
to me disguised as Rem!
Was that your power?!
N-No!
I-If I looked like s-someone else,
it's because... y-you wanted
to see me that way...
What?!
I-I didn't w-want to, but Echidna-chan said
a-all I had to do was dote on you...
So Echidna is the one behind all this?!
Going any further will endanger your life.
Carmilla's "Faceless Bride"
makes one forget to breathe
when in her presence.
In the end, it even makes
your heart stop beating.
What the hell have you been plotting, Echidna?
Isn't that obvious?
An evil scheme, of course. I am a witch.
Why did you do something like that?
Because it was the most
effective method, that's why.
If I'd left things alone,
your mind would've worn away
to nothing in the trial.
So you're telling me you did that to save me?
I can't make any excuses for the fact
that I wounded your heart as a result.
I've resigned myself to accepting your rage.
I know what it is you want to know
more than anything right now.
Allow me to explain the trial.
Just like the first one,
the second trial puts you in a world
recreated from your memories.
It's a thoroughly
well-constructed unreality.
Then—
However...
Your Return by Death is the
Witch of Envy's Authority.
Basically, only she knows
whether the things you saw
in your second trial happened in some reality.
You mean all that stuff might
have actually happened?
I'm only saying it's a possibility.
Instead of counting the many people
you may have failed to save,
you should focus on counting
the many you have saved.
Idealistic clichés like that don't help!
I know that you have given
all of your strength,
physical and mental, to survive thus far.
Not a single thing you've experienced on
your way to this point has been a waste.
You have arrived at this moment by
doing everything in your power,
at the risk of your own life.
That's something you should be proud of.
Why do you keep trying to help me like this?
I think it's a little mean to force
a girl to spell that out for you.
Would you be willing to form a
contract with me, Natsuki Subaru?
A contract?
Yes, a formal contract with the Witch of Greed.
Would you enter into one with me?
What happens if I do?
It's very simple.
From now on, whenever you run into
an obstacle you can't overcome,
when you feel you're being crushed
by the weight of your sins,
I will give you my support.
I'm confident in the amount
of knowledge I have.
I should be able to come up with a way
for you to deal with any problem.
Above all, I can share in your
Return by Death ability.
What does that mean?
You're actually telling me the selling
points of making a contract with you?
I think it only makes sense to
explain the merits of such an act.
All the better for me if it makes you
lean toward agreeing to it at all.
It's all calculated.
That might not be such a bad idea.
Meaning?!
I mean, uh... right.
If you absolutely insist, I wouldn't
mind entering into a contract—
It's a little late to try and play it cool now!
Anyway, how would we form this contract?
To establish a formal contract,
you and I need to form
a bond between our souls.
First, we raise our palms
to each other, like this.
Wh-Wha?!
I'm gonna have to...
put a stop to that contract.
The Witch of Wrath?!
I won't accept it!
So you're after him, too?
I suppose you're jealous.
Stop teasing me!
I'm outraged! I'm indignant!
I'm absolutely boiling with anger!
How is she even here?
Don't you have to swap places with the
other witches to let them appear?
That's a lie!
She's a bad-natured jerk who plays
mean tricks like that for no reason!
Well, I didn't want to just keep
popping witches into existence,
and let one of them take you from me.
Stop being taken in so easily by
all of Echidna's smooth-talking!
It pisses me off!
Also, she hasn't even told you
what parts of that contract...
would be...
bad...
for you!
H-Hang on! "Bad" for me?!
She's talking about your payment
for contracting with me.
I think calling it a bad thing is
a bit of an exaggeration, though.
What is it you want from me, then?
What payment do I have to give?
It's very simple.
Everything you feel, everything you think,
everything that remains in your heart,
the future as you know it,
anything you accomplish,
all the potential within you,
all the fruit of the unknown that
is borne from your very existence...
I want a taste of it.
Th-That's all true...
B-But don't assume that she
just t-told you everything...
The Witch of Lust?
E-Echidna-chan... isn't lying...
But there's a lot... she's hiding from you.
Don't bother listening to
these two, Natsuki Subaru.
Once you have formed a contract with me,
I will, without fail, guide you
to the future you desire.
This wouldn't be the promise you always
precede with "In the end..." would it?
And who are you?!
The Witch of Sloth, Sekhmet.
Just letting you know my name,
for the record and all.
You're the sixth...
I'm only here as a watchdog to
preserve the fairness of this place.
But I will fulfill my obligation to her.
Oh, Baru, you're here?
Is everyone here now? That's unusual!
It's been a long time since we had a tea party.
You should have invited me, too.
Why do you guys keep appearing
one after another?!
What do you want from me?!
I believe I told you already.
It's the promise that's always
preceded by "In the end..."
"In the end"?
Echidna, you said you'd guide me to
the best possible future, didn't you?
Yes, I did. It was true.
And with your help, would I arrive
at the best possible future
by following the best possible path?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Answer me, Echidna!
Answer me, Witch of Greed!
For the purpose of attaining
the future you desire,
you must accept any sacrifices
made along the way.
Is that not the resolution
you made, Natsuki Subaru?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
No, I will not wait.
You are the one who needs
to understand better.
Just think about it!
The Return by Death Authority you
possess is a tremendous thing.
You do not fully understand
how truly useful it is.
It allows you to restart the world all you
want until you reach your desired future.
It's the embodiment of the ultimate
ideal any seeker could wish for!
Of course, I won't force
you to Return by Death.
You will use it to achieve
the result you desire,
and I will lend you all the wisdom
you need to fulfill your wish.
I expect all the results that
come about in the process
to contribute vastly to the
satisfaction of my curiosity!
We will agonize over, struggle with,
and solve the same problems together.
We will have the optimal
relationship to achieve that!
As I make use of your power,
I want you to use me to achieve your
best possible future, too.
My maidenly heart's affection for you
and desire to help you are real.
I'd be more than content to have
you treat me as a convenience.
If it's what you want, you're welcome
to use my body for your comfort!
I gladly offer it to you!
I will give you the strength to
move forward with my words.
Whether you want comfort,
motivation, or love,
or even hatred, I will give it
all to you. I can give it all!
You like girls who give you
everything, don't you?
You need me!
No one but you can satisfy
my curiosity now.
If you use your power to save someone,
I want you to save me.
I cannot control my own greed!
No matter what happens, I will guide
you to the future you desire.
I swear it! I absolutely swear it!
And the Sanctuary's liberation
lies beyond that.
You can save everyone trapped there—the one
you love and all those you care about!
For that purpose, I want
you to take me, use me,
and rob me of all the greed you want,
so we can take hold of our future!
That is all I want from you,
all I desire from you,
and all I offer in return.
I have now told you everything... truly,
every last detail, with passion.
This might be close to love.
It's a vow of love!
And how will you respond to my love?
I want your answer!
That is one of the answers that will
satisfy my curiosity, after all.
Echidna...
Yes?
You're going to use me?
I am.
And you can do the same to me.
That's what this contract is for.
If you want to criticize
me for using it as a means
to keep you as my own, I'll accept that.
It's the truth, after all.
It's not as if I never considered
that your intentions might not be 100% good.
But... that's just way beyond the pale!
I don't quite understand what
you find so problematic.
Everything about your attitude
is so infantile and shallow!
It's all completely superficial!
When you laugh, even when
you're mad, your attitude is...
Echidna, you're incapable of
understanding how anyone else feels!
This is one of those times
when you could get angry...
I see. You have taught me much.
When we next have a chance...
I will do just that.
But first, why not have a seat?
I'd like to discuss our contract a bit more.
I just remembered...
There was one thing I wanted to
ask you when I saw you again.
Oh? What might that be?
Once I hear your answer, I think
I'll be able to make a choice.
You know Beatrice, don't you?
Yes, I do.
I was deeply involved in her birth, after all.
Beatrice has lived her life under a contract
forcing her to wait for "that person."
I believe that contract was with you.
True. I'm the one who ordered her to protect
the forbidden library and await
the one who would come for her.
Then who is "that person"?
How can I set her free?
Good question! Whoever could it be?
What?!
You... You're saying you don't even
know who Beatrice is waiting for?!
I really don't know.
But why?
Weren't you the one who told
her to wait for them?!
You've made quite a misunderstanding.
I didn't force Beatrice to make that promise
so she'd give the forbidden
library to "that person."
What?
That wasn't my goal at all.
By making her promise to wait for
"that person" to come to her,
I want to find out who she will choose
to be "that person."
Of course, her staying there for 400 years
without choosing anyone is one result of that.
Her inability to choose anyone
so easily all this time
and wanting to die as she agonized over
whether to keep upholding the contract or not
are also results of that.
And how do you feel about that?
I think it's wonderful.
Echidna...
You are a witch!
You're an unfathomable monster
beyond all comprehension!
And I...
I won't take your hand.
I know whose hand I want to take.
There's a girl who's been
tied down by the words
you spoke out of pure
curiosity, without malice.
My mind's made up.
I'm going to take her hand.
I won't go with you.
She's here.
N-No!
I have nothing to do with any of this!
A really troublesome girl just showed up
at a troubling time to start some trouble.
Oh! I'm feeling very, very hungry!
Hey! It's Tella!
Long time no see!
The Witches' Tea Party